<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Minimal Viable Book]]></title>
  <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-13T15:29:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://minimalviablebook.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Find a reader]]></title>
    <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/find-a-reader/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-14T08:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/find-a-reader</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This blog is &lsquo;sequential&rsquo;.  Please start at <a href="the%20beginning">site-launch</a> and work forward from there with the bottom-right-hand arrows.</p>

<p>Now that you have started your book with some writings in &lsquo;{Title}_1.doc&rsquo;, your next goal is to find a reader.  To this reader you will say</p>

<blockquote><p>This is a start
of my book {Title}.  I would like you to read it and give me your personal feedback and insights.  What do you like and dislike about the writing?  Are
there any words or phrases that you don&rsquo;t understand?  What do you think of the tone?  What do you think of the title?</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t worry about &lsquo;editing&rsquo; the
writing, I will pay for a commercial editor.  But feel free to do so if you need to as part of reading the book</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Start by writing]]></title>
    <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/start-by-writing/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-13T08:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/start-by-writing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This may seem to be a no-brainer, but you start a book by writing.  It doesn&rsquo;t have to be much of anything.  It could be <em>complete crap</em>
I encourage you to write <em>complete crap</em> if that is all you can do.  Because writing anything is the start.  Everything until that point is just dreaming.
You want to be an auther right?  So go write!  One paragraph.  &ldquo;It was a dark and stormy night&hellip;&rdquo; or whatever.  I will wait.</p>

<p>(Next day)</p>

<p>OK.  Did you write something?  Yes!  Awesome!</p>

<p>If not, let us try this again.  The day I became an author was a Monday in May.  I had been biking around Google for many months (even years) and while biking
all those months/years I had been telling myself stories.  I would write stories in my head and listen to them in my head.</p>

<p>But this particular Monday when I got home, I did something &lsquo;new&rsquo;.  I wrote down the story that I just had in my head.  I created a word document:</p>

<ul>
<li> SlumsOfPA_mlf1a1.doc</li>
</ul>


<p>The first part is the title of the book: &ldquo;The Slums of Palo Alto&rdquo;.  The second part after the underscore are my initials and then a version counter &lsquo;1a1&rsquo;.  Together
these form part of a vector-clock, but that is a different topic.  If you ignore the &lsquo;mlf1a&rsquo; we get a file named:</p>

<ul>
<li> SlumsOfPA_1.doc</li>
</ul>


<p>OK.  Now you go and create a file named &lsquo;{Title}_1.doc&rsquo; where you replace the &lsquo;{Title}&rsquo; part with your actual title.  I will wait.</p>

<p>Note that some day in the future you can change your title.  So don&rsquo;t worry about the title being &ldquo;final&rdquo;, it is just a title.</p>

<p>Now into this file type the title in full as the very first line.  For me it is:</p>

<blockquote><p>The Slums of Palo Alto</p></blockquote>

<p>Decide if you need a subtitle, and if you have one (right this moment, doesn&rsquo;t have to be fine) write it:</p>

<blockquote><p>How to be ecstatically happy after ten failed startups</p></blockquote>

<p>Hit a couple &lsquo;enters&rsquo; to get some space.</p>

<p>And now the most important part.  Just write!  It doesn&rsquo;t have to be the start, it should just be a paragraph that <em>could possibly</em> be in your book, somewhere.</p>

<blockquote><p>The putting green on the balcony overlooked Santa Monica pier.  We were in the suite previously owned by Lawrence Welk, and could watch the taping of Bay Watch every Monday.  During the day it was incredibly beautiful… it was the first of a series of too beautiful to believe buildings that would affect my life.  At night it was a bit scary.  We were building a news palace for a Saudi Prince.</p></blockquote>

<p>Now you do the same.  I will wait.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-12T08:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been writing a book <a href="http://slumsofpaloalto.com/.">http://slumsofpaloalto.com/.</a>  How I started, progressed, and finished is <em>very different</em> from
how others think about books and publishing.  It is insanely different.  And insanely better.  I hope describing it helps you.</p>

<p>I am mostly going to walk through chronologically because I think I generally did things in the right order.  So each blog
posting will be a replay of time.</p>

<p>An important thing to know about me is that I am a &ldquo;startup specialist&rdquo;.  I launch companies and try to get them to a point
where other people want to buy them or they can &ldquo;go public&rdquo; on stock market.  This is the angle I am coming from.  I am certainly
a capable writer, but that is mostly technically oriented.  And the book I wrote is an &ldquo;augmented memoir&rdquo;, which is a significantly
easier thing to write than a novel or really any other form of book.</p>

<p>I can not help you be a great writer.  I may be a horrible writer.  But in a ridiculously short period of time, other people were
reading my <em>book</em>.  An actual book.  Not a manuscript, draft, etc.  It was a book.</p>

<p>That ridiculously short period of time from having <em>never written a book</em> to <em>having a book</em> that others are reading?  One month!  By two months I was at 150 pages
and had mailed my book to Stephen Colbert, John Stewart, and Sheryl Sandberg.  Plus dozens of people that I could easily reach in my home town.  And the time-lines
continue with that insane speed.  Oh, and I was rejected by 42 literary agents in that same period.  More than a dozen by the end of one month.  So the time-lines
and <em>effectiveness</em> are insanely different.</p>

<p>When normal is not giving you what you want, insanity (&ldquo;think different&rdquo;) can be insanely better!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
