<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Minimal Viable Book]]></title>
  <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-12T10:07:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://minimalviablebook.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-12T18:15:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://minimalviablebook.com/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been writing a book <a href="http://slumsofpaloalto.com/.">http://slumsofpaloalto.com/.</a>  How I started, progressed, and finished is <em>very different</em> from
how others think about books and publishing.  It is insanely different.  And insanely better.  I hope describing it helps you.</p>

<p>I am mostly going to walk through chronologically because I think I generally did things in the right order.  So each blog
posting will be a replay of time.</p>

<p>An important thing to know about me is that I am a &ldquo;startup specialist&rdquo;.  I launch companies and try to get them to a point
where other people want to buy them or they can &ldquo;go public&rdquo; on stock market.  This is the angle I am coming from.  I am certainly
a capable writer, but they is mostly technically oriented.  And the book I wrote is an &ldquo;augmented memoir&rdquo;, which is a significantly
easier thing to write than a novel or really any other form of book.</p>

<p>I can not help you be a great writer.  I may be a horrible writer.  But in a ridiculously short period of time, other people were
reading my <em>book</em>.  An actual book.  Not a manuscript, draft, etc.  It was a book.</p>

<p>That ridiculously short period of time from having <em>never written a book</em> to <em>having a book</em> that others are reading.  One month.  By two months I was at 150 pages
and had mailed my book to Stephen Colbert, John Stewart, and Sheryl Sandberg.  Plus dozens of people that I could easily reach in my home town.  And the timelines
continue with that insane speed.  Oh, and I was rejected by 42 literary agents in that same period.  More than a dozen by the end of one month.  So the timelines
and <em>effectiveness</em> are insanely different.</p>

<p>When normal is not giving you what you want, Insanity can be insanely better!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
